That means it's high noon in old
Cheyenne.
Like to call the July 21st meeting of
the finance committee
of the Cheyenne City Council to order.
When you're making a public comment,
clearly identify yourself. Make sure
your cell phones are on mute if you're
in the room here. Uh make public comment
online. Use the raised hand function in
making comments in person. Approach the
podium, turn on the microphone and
identify yourself. At the end of the
agenda, there will be no additional
business discussed. And as usual, all
communications go through the chairman
and I will allow a little more leniency
today on the quorum since it's frontier
days. So with that, Adam clerk, first
item, especially for the chairman. Yeah.
Number 7A, application for a bar and
grill liquor license filed with the city
clerk's office for Cheyenne Railard LLC
doing business as the Railard, Cheyenne,
115 West 15th Street, Cheyenne, Wyoming.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman, members of the committee,
Kylie Soden, city clerk. The item before
you is an application for a bar and
grill liquor license submitted by
Cheyenne Railard LLC doing business as
the Railard Cheyenne to be located at
115 West 15th Street. The application
has been reviewed by applicable city
departments and the Wyoming Liquor
Division and requirements for the
application have been met. I can answer
any questions you may have and I believe
the applicant is available as well.
>> Comments or questions from the committee
for the clerk?
Okay, we'll go to public comment in the
room with Would the
You like to do any comment to the
committee on your restaurant?
You don't have to.
You tell us about that train wreck
burger.
>> Okay. Turn on the microphone, please,
and and identify yourself. I'm Chris
O'Brien. I'm the owner of the railard.
So happy to answer any questions if you
need me to, but you guys have a big
agenda here, so I don't want to be in
your way.
>> Uh, Council Wolf.
>> Ah, thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through
you. Um, thank you, sir. Um, I dropped
in there the other night and, uh, looked
around and, uh, was very busy. So, um,
thank you for doing that. All of that
brewing equipment, is that coming out?
We are letting the chips fall for
accomplice in their bankruptcy. Once
that's done, then we'll help the depot
do whatever they need to do to get
everything out.
>> I see.
>> Hopefully Depot gets to sell it and get
back with the road.
>> Okay. All right. Thank you. Thank you,
Mr. Chairman.
>> I'm sure you'll be real busy tomorrow.
Uh we'll have that guy do on that train
wreck.
>> He got about halfway. He He left
fighting tears. It's It's not really
meant to be eaten by one person. So, but
he gave it a good shot. Good.
Maybe that guy that used to do Man Verse
Food will come here to try it.
>> We We've had two competitive eaters come
in to have them before. They're the only
two people that have finished them. So,
I don't I don't want to know what they
do to do that, but
>> Thank you.
>> Yep.
>> Any other public comment on this line uh
item in the room?
>> Any public comment online?
Any public comment online?
Seeing none, we'll come back to the
committee. What's your pleasure,
>> Mr. Chairman?
>> Councilman Renie,
>> I moved to approve the application.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Renie, second
by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion?
>> All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> And that that motion is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item.
>> Number 23. Resolution adopting the 2026
program year annual action plan for the
city of Cheyenne community development
block grant entitlement program
>> staff report.
>> Welcome m.
>> Good afternoon Mr. Chairman and members
of the finance committee. My name is
Elizabeth Finneo. I'm the economic
resource administrator for the city of
Cheyenne. Before you today is the
program year 26 annual action plan for
the city of Cheyenne's community
development block grant which is
administered through the US department
of housing and urban development known
as HUD. The city of Cheyenne is an
entitlement community that receives an
annual allocation from HUD and the
annual action plan is a requirement of
receiving that allocation.
This plan details the activities the
city intends to fund during the program
year and the amounts allocated toward
them. The 2026 annual action plan
funding sources are as follows. $418,483
is our annual our PY26 annual allocation
from HUD. $77,094
is returned revenue from the Cheyenne
Senior Center change of use.2 $245,599
is prior year reallocated funding. The
total available funding for our PY26 is
$741,176.
The 2026 action annual action plan
projects are as follows. $83,696
will go to CDBG program administration.
$99,000 will go to the Healthworks
elevator replacement project.
$30,360
will go to my front door for exterior
renovations.
$54,648
towards my front door for interior
renovations.
$239,765
will go to PY26 safe routes to school
city of Cheyenne projects for to be
determined schools.
$126,720
will go to Family Promise for
Rehabilitation.
$55,000 will go to Cheyenne Seniors
Housing Heritage Court Apartments
Rehabilitation.
And then $51,987
has been allocated to public service
projects that are yet to be determined.
And I stand for any questions.
>> Any questions from the committee for
staff?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room.
Any public comment in the room?
Public comment online.
Any public comment online?
Seeing none. Back to the committee.
What's your pleasure?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to adopt.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Moody, second
by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion?
>> Just real quick, Mr.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Yeah. Thanks, Mr. Chairman. Through you.
Uh just for the public to know it's on
pages uh 24 25 26 that was described of
uh breaking down all those numbers just
so that way you can see them for
yourself and it is online. Thank you.
>> All those in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Any opposed? Seeing that that vote is
unanimous. The recommendation of the
finance committee at the next meeting of
the governing body will be to adopt.
Next item
>> number 24 resolution authorizing the
mayor to execute a memorandum of
understanding with participating
counties, cities, and towns regarding
the allocation of impact assistance
funds associated with the Laraming range
wind project application before the
industrial sighting council.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman, committee members, John
Brody, city attorney. Uh this is just a
resolution to authorize anou with the
impacted jurisdictions
tied to the Laramie wind uh energy
project uh just I guess northwest here
of Cheyenne. Um we are in um we are
currently in conversations with Plaque
County Chugwater and Laramie County to
get thatou put together. Based on our
initial assessment, um we're thinking
it's going to be a little under
$700,000. Uh in the that'll be the
amount we're requesting,
Mr. Chairman. It's based on the cost of
service approach that we've um employed
in the last I guess four energy
projects. Um and the industrial sighting
council has uh always granted those
requests using that approach. Um the ISC
hearing itself will be August 31st. Um
so we are diligently preparing for that
hearing. I'm happy to answer any
questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for the city attorney? I
>> have a question.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Thank you.
Thank you, Mr. Brody. And it's okay if
you can answer, but if somebody else
can. Is this the same wind project that
was rejected by the county commissioners
back in September of 2025?
>> Mr. Chairman, Councilman Moody, I
believe so, but I would I would want to
double check and get back to you just to
make sure 100%.
>> Thank you.
>> Any other comments or questions for our
city attorney?
>> Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room. Any public comment in the
room?
Any public comment online?
Any public comment online? Seeing none,
we'll come back to the committee. What's
your pleasure?
Uh, [clears throat]
Mr. Chairman, I move to adopt. Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Wolf, second by
Councilman Renie. Any further
discussion?
>> All in favor signify. Signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> Any opposed?
>> No.
>> The recommendation of the finance
committee at the next meeting of the
governing body will be to adopt with
Councilman Moody voting no. Next item
>> number 26E. Agreement between the city
of Cheyenne and Larmy County for animal
control services.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon, Mr. Chairman,
committeemen. Um, what you have before
you today is the animal control contract
between the city of Cheyenne and Larry
County to provide control services for
the unincorporated communities. The
amount's $156,850
paid to the city of Cheyenne on behalf
of Lurmy County and I would ask for your
consideration and I'll stand for
questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for the director?
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Mr. Chairman, thank you through you. Um,
Mr. Fountain, thank you. Um, how long
have we had this agreement with the
county?
>> Mr. Chairman, through you. The agreement
has been there since we began the
control services here at the city of
Cheyenne. So when it left the animal
shelter, the agreement was to work uh
side by side together to provide
services to the county, the same
services provided to the city.
>> Thank you.
>> Any further questions for the director?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room.
Any public comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
public. I'm in online.
Seeing none, we'll come back to the
committee. What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to adopt the
agreement.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Rainey. Second
by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion?
All in favor?
>> Mr. Chairman.
>> Councilman Rainy.
>> Reading the notes. It should be I move
to approve in the amount of 156850 for
pardon me.
>> Yes.
Mr. Chairman, the motion should be to
approve in the amount of $156,850
for one year.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Ren,
second by Councilman Wolf. Any further
comments?
>> All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Any opposed? Seeing that that vote's
unanimous, the recommendation of the
finance committee at the next meeting of
the governing body will be to approve in
the amount of 156,000
$850 for one year. Next item
>> number 26F agreement between the city of
Cheyenne, Laramie County, and the
Cheyenne Animal Shelter for Animal
Shelter Services.
>> Staff report. Good afternoon, Mr.
Chairman. Uh committee members, Eric
Fountain, director of compliance. Um
I've been asked to uh introduce this
item only in the fact that um Miss uh
Tenant is out of town. Um but she does
thank you for the consideration and
thank you for the partnership on behalf
of the Cheyenne Animal Shelter. Um the
request is $650,000. It's a one-year
contract versus three. That is the only
change to the contract is the time. Um
otherwise we would ask for
consideration. I would stand for
questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for the director?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment.
Councilman Renie,
>> just to make sure, like the little note
said, we were supposed to prove the
amount for one year, but it's a
three-year contract. Is that correct?
>> U Mr. Chairman, you know, it's a
one-year contract. It has been a three,
but it's a one year now.
>> So, I just heard it in reverse.
>> No problem.
>> Thank you.
>> So, the only thing that changed was the
amount and the date,
>> Mr. Chairman. That's correct.
>> Okay. Any public comment in the room?
Public comment. Any public comment
online on this item?
Public comment online.
We'll come back to the committee. Any
comments or questions? Councilman Moody.
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve an
amount not to exceed $650,000
for one year.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
second by Councilman Wolf.
Any further comments? [snorts]
All in favor signify by saying.
No.
Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve in an amount not
to exceed $650,000
for one year. Next item, please.
>> Number 26G. Contract between the city of
Cheyenne, Larry County Sheriff's
Department, and Larry County for housing
prisoners at the Laramie County
Detention Center.
>> Staff report.
Mr. Chairman, members of the committee,
what you have before you is the contract
with the jail um to house adult
prisoners. We we used to redo this every
year. Last time was a two-year contract.
So, we're doing a two-year contract
again. The only significant change is
the amounts. They raised it to $135 a
night from 125 and $70 for book and
release is basically 12-hour holds that
don't stay a whole a whole night to 70
from 60. And I stand for any questions.
Oh yeah, Captain David James. Shine
Police Department.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for Captain James? Councilman
Wolf.
>> Uh thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through you,
um we've got this big jail renovation
captain, uh that's on the ballot. Um
would this be at all affected by that?
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, through you. No, this
um this shouldn't affect much of that.
When I spoke with the the chief deputy
of the jail, they explained one I mean
just inflation in general being one big
reason why they're asking for an
increase and another one their cost per
prisoner has gone up that their expenses
um a lot of it has to do with nursing
staff and food prices and all all the
other expenses at the jail.
>> Any further comments or questions?
See none, we'll go to public comment in
the room. Any public comment in the
room?
Public comment online.
Any public comment online?
>> Okay, seeing none, we'll come back to
the committee. What's your pleasure,
>> Mr. Chairman?
>> Yes, Councilman Wolf.
>> Thank you. Um I move to approve um
and uh the amounts of $135
per prisoner per day, 70 dollars per
prisoner for book and release and
transportation rates as applicical of
725 uh cents per mile and uh $55 per off
hour per officer.
>> Second. It's
>> been moved by council Wolf, second by
Councilman Moody. Any further
discussion?
All in favor signify by saying I.
Seeing that that votes unanimous, the
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item
>> number 26H, juvenile h housing agreement
between the city of Cheyenne and the
Laramie County Sheriff's Department for
the housing of juvenile detaininees and
the Laramie County Juvenile Services
Center.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman, members of committee,
Captain David James, Cheyenne Police
Department. Uh this is very similar.
This for the juvenile housing agreement
uh for juvenile arrestes. Uh this is
also a two-year contract with the
sheriff's department. Uh this one has
gone up a little more than that because
they went several years without having
an increase. Uh it went from $195 a
night to $225 a night and uh there
wasn't a book and release fee before and
that's $70 a night and the
transportation rem rates remain the
same. And I stand for any questions,
>> comments or questions from the
committee. Just a quick question.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Yeah. Thank you. Thank Captain James. Uh
I know it's a little more for juveniles.
Uh just clarification also for the
public. Is it because of the social
services available to them as well? Is
that why it's a little higher than it is
for adults?
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, through you absolutely
the the costs for juveniles are a lot
higher because it includes education as
well as nursing and housing and food and
everything else. There's a lot more
expense to it. And so everybody knows,
we arrest very few juveniles. Uh usually
about 50 a year and most of those um are
charged into the state. We very rarely
charge anyone city ordinance and and
arrest for juveniles. We follow federal
federal guidelines on juveniles and how
we handle juveniles. So very few um I
think I checked last year we had about
30 total nights the juveniles stayed on
municipal charges and the majority of
those were posts sentencing charges. So
the municipal judge sent them to jail.
So very very seldom um does one of our
officers arrest someone and charge them
into city court. It's usually county.
And when that happens, the county picks
up the entire cost.
>> Any further questions or comments?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room. Any public comment in the
room?
Seeing none, any public comment online?
Public comment online.
Seeing none, come back to the committee.
What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve um for
the rates of $225 per juvenile per day,
75 $70 per juvenile for book and
release, and transportation rates as
applicable of.725
cents per mile and $55 per hour per
officer. Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
second by Councilman Moody. Any further
discussion? All in favor signify by
saying I.
Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item
>> number 26 I. Grant agreement between the
city of Cheyenne office of youth
alternatives and Cheyenne Regional
Medical Center DRMC for suicide homicide
assessments and prevention services.
staff report.
Jamie, you can go ahead.
Jamie, you might be muted.
>> You're unmuted.
>> Okay. Thank you. Uh chairman and members
of the finance committee, I'm Jamie
Eaton with the prevention services
coordinator um with Office of Youth
Alternatives. The action before you
today is the grant agreement with the
Office of Youth Alternatives and uh
Cheyenne Regional Medical Center. It's
to provide suicide and homicide
assessments as well as prevention
services for the youth in our community.
Um I stand before you if you have any
questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for staff?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room. Any public comment in the
room?
Seeing none, public comment online.
Any public comment online?
None. We'll come back to the committee.
What's your pleasure?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to approve
these services are budgeted not to
exceed 44,000 annually through June 15
of 2028.
Been a motion moved by Councilman Moody,
second by Councilman Rainey. Any further
discussion?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item
>> number 26J. Professional services
agreement between the city of Cheyenne
and Terracon Consultants Incorporated
for landfill leakate system design,
modification, and maintenance.
>> Staff report.
Good afternoon, chairman and members of
the committee. Sam Katrini, public works
landfill manager. Uh this is a a
professional services agreement that we
have with Terracon Consultants uh for
taking care of our leeches system at the
landfill. It'll bear a cost up to
$85,000 for two years and it'll be paid
for solid waste fund uh through the
solid waste fund. Uh if you have any
questions, I'm here.
>> Any questions for the committee for
staff?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room. Any public comment in the
room?
Seeing none, any public comment online?
Public comment online.
Seeing none, back to the committee.
What's your pleasure,
>> Mr. Chairman?
>> I move to approve an amount not to
exceed $85,000.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Rainey,
second by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item
>> number 27D, consideration of bid number
S-22-26
for a contract between the city of
Cheyenne and Legacy Construction Group
for the Christensen Road detention
erosion mitigation project.
>> Staff report. Good afternoon, Chairman
Esel and members of the finance
committee. Tom Cobbs, city engineer. Um,
before you and for your consideration is
the bid that came back from you. I asked
for a two-week postponement for this is
for repair an erosion repair that's
occurring on the south side of the Union
Pacific Railroad tracks north of Lowe's
distribution center. We have a detention
pond. I do not have an answer yet from
the Union Pacific Railroad Surprise. So,
I am going to request another twoe
postponement. And at that time, if we
don't receive any word, I'm going to ask
to reject the bids and rebid this at a
time when we get an answer from the
railroad.
>> Any that I'll have any questions that
you'd like to have for me?
>> Any comments or questions for
>> Councilman Moody?
>> Um, thank you, Mr. Turner 3. Thank you,
sir. Just a question. If let's say the
railroad does not get back to us, how
high of a priority would you say we
definitely need to get this done? Is it
like a quickly because of the potential
danger of flooding?
>> Chairman Esco through you to Councilman
Moody. Sir, it's it's been sitting out
there for about three years. So, I'm not
It's It needs to be completed because
there are some utility lines that are
south of the railroad. It would be in
the railroad's best interest for us to
move forward quicker. Um but, um I think
from a danger standpoint, none none as
far as flooding. It'll get to the
retention pond.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Any other comments or questions from the
committee?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room. Any public comment in the
room on this item?
Public comment online.
Any public comment online?
Seeing none, back to the committee.
What's your pleasure?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I uh move to um
postpone for a period of two weeks.
>> We need a motion. We need a motion. I'm
sorry.
>> U Mr. Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the
bid and then an amount not to exceed
$314,95.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
second by Councilman Moody.
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to postpone for
two weeks.
>> Second.
>> Moved by Councilman Moody, second by
Councilman Wolf to postpone for two
weeks. All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
Assume that that votes unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to postpone for two weeks. Next
item
>> number 27E. Consideration of bid number
S-23-26
for a contract between the city of
Cheyenne and JTL Group Incorporated
doing business as Knife River for the
Christensen Road sub settlement bridge
approach project.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon, Chairman Esel, members
of finance committee. Tom Cobb, city
engineer. before you and for your
consideration is bid S-23-26
for a contract within the city of
Cheyenne and JTO Group known as Knife
River. Um again, this is in the same
area that we discussed previously. This
is actually then north the Christensen
Bridge. Um when we evaluated this, there
was some settlement that occurred
approximately year three, three and a
half after we finished the bridge
project. Um this will fix that
settlement, redo the sidewalk. Um, and
also there's a manhole north of this
location that this will also repair. Um,
we received four bids. Um, myself, Mr.
Clone have reviewed those bids and we
recommend that you accept the bid in the
amount of $224,369
and I'll take any questions you might
have of me.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for our city engineer?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room. Any public comment in the
room?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
online.
Any public comment online?
>> Back to the committee. What's your
pleasure?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the
bid amount not to exceed $224,3690.
>> Second.
Been
>> moved by Councilman Moody. Second by
Councilman Wolf. Any further discuss
discussion?
All in favor signify by saying I.
Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to accept the bid. Next
item
>> number 27F, consideration of bid number
S-24-26
for a contract between the city of
Cheyenne and Bone Dry Commercial Roofing
Incorporated for the 2026 various roof
replacements project. Staff report.
>> The microphone's off.
>> Good afternoon. Uh Stevie, our
facilities manager. Contract before you
today is to replace various roof
sections at six uh separate city
locations. Those locations are um George
Cox parking facility, Spiker parking
facility,
um Pioneer Park Center, um Municipal
Retention Building, Ice and Event
Center, and Street Alley Shop. Staff
recommendation is to accept the bid in
the amount of $283,130.
I will stand for questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room.
>> Uh you Mr. Chairman, Michael White. Um I
have a a few concerns. Um B basically
asking a couple questions.
um 1% sales tax affects all of us and
I'm a little concerned where I have
talked to TJ in the past and to find out
if these contractors are even licensed
before they give a bid to the city. In
addition, we have a number of local
roofing contractors.
Um so one question would be where is
bone dry commercial roofing from? And
number two, I realize that this is not
part of your entity, but uh to me before
this even comes to a vote, these people
should be verified that they're a
licensed contractor. Thank you.
>> You have an answer for us, TJ.
>> Uh chair threw you to the committee into
the comments. This is TJ Bartle,
purchasing manager. Uh just to confirm,
we did uh this contractor is licensed
with the city building office. So they
are ready. They're good to go there. And
I guess to the comment on local roofers.
Uh we did do this project as a mandatory
attendance pre-bid meeting. I bet we had
15 or 20 contractors present and Bone
Dry was our low bidder with or without
um Bonery was the low bidder with
application of the 5% resid residency
preference. So they were our lowest
responsive bidder and we recommend them
for award for the project. Councilman
Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Chair. Through you,
uh, thank you, sir. Where is uh, Bone
Drive commercial roofing exactly? Like
where is their where's their
headquarters at? Chair through you to
Councilman Moody. Sorry, I forgot to
answer that part of the question. I was
pulling it up while I was talking.
They're they have an office located in
Fort Collins, Colorado.
>> Any further comments or questions for
staff?
Well, back to public comment. Uh,
any more public comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
Okay, we'll come back to the committee.
What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chairman, uh, I move to accept the
bid in the matter not to exceed
$283,130.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Wolf, second by
Councilman Renie. Any further
discussion?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> No.
>> The recommendation of the finance
committee at the next meeting of the
governing body will be to accept the bid
with Councilman Moody voting no. Next
item
>> number 27G. Consideration of bin number
E-26-26
for furnishing 10 new four-door 2026
2027 model utility police and
interceptors for the Cheyenne Police
Department.
>> Steph,
>> good afternoon. Um, chair, members of
members of the committee, action that
you have before you, I'm Lieutenant Brad
Danny from the Shan Police Department of
Fleet um, uh, support services
lieutenant, and we have consideration of
a bin for furnishing the 10 new
four-door police interceptors for the
Shyam Police Department.
Two bids that we received, one from
Fremont Motor Company out of Lander,
Wyoming, one from Duval Ford out of
Jacksonville, Florida. I personally
reviewed these bids along with Brian
Bell from Fleet Maintenance and our
recommendation is to accept the lowest
responsive bid from Duval Ford and the
total request of $684,758
and I stand for any further questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for staff? Councilman Wolf.
>> Uh Mr. Chairman through you. Thank you.
Um uh thank you very much. Um do we have
experience with this company Duval for
Mr. Chairman through you? Uh we
absolutely do. They did our last bid.
We're extremely happy with their
product. Um a lot of improvements over
the past couple years. Um it's an
allincclusive
thing. So we used to order our vehicles
and then we send them out for upfitting
and we noticed a lot of issues with that
through the past. So Dub Ford does a
one-stop shop and we are been extremely
happy with them.
>> Great. Yes.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Mr. Lee.
>> Any further questions or comments?
It will go out to public comment in the
room. Any public comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
Public comment online. Okay. Back to the
committee. What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept a bid
from Duval Ford LLC, Jacksonville,
Florida, and amount not to exceed
684,7580.
>> Second. There been moved by Councilman
Moody, second by Councilman Wolf. Any
further discussion? Councilman Moody.
>> Yep. Thanks, Chair through you. Um,
probably wondering again the last one
because it was not a local company, but
it's roofing again. This is public
safety and I've looked them up. They're
nationwide. They do it for almost a lot
of police departments. So, this is a lot
different. So, thank you.
>> All in favor signify by saying I.
Seeing that that vote is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to accept the bid. Next
item
>> number 27H, consideration of bid number
E-27-26
for furnishing one new 2026 or newer
gross
350 sweeper for the street and alley
department or street and alley division.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon, Mr. Chairman, members of
the committee. Bill Gonzalez public
works. Before you is a consideration of
a bid to replace a brace highway broom
is what it's called. And what we
generally use this for is sweeping the
road prior to uh overlaying or when we
mill a road. It takes all of the fine
stuff off of it. It pushes it off to the
side. Um we received a bid for
$89,758.32.
And what we are replacing is a 23y old
machine that has been in service that
long. So I'd stand for any questions.
Any comments or questions from the
committee or staff?
Seeing none, any public comment in the
room?
Any public comment in the room? Any
public comment online?
Any public comment online? Back to the
committee. What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the bid
from Transource Truck and Equipment of
Casper in the amount not to exceed
$81,758.32.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Rainey,
second by Councilman Moody. All in favor
signify by saying I.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to accept the bid. Next
item
>> number 27 I consideration of bid number
E-28-26
for the surplus sale of evidence seized
firearms and department owned firearms
for the Cheyenne Police Department.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon chairman committee. I'm
Detective Matthew Ryan with the Cheyenne
Police Department. Uh before you is
consideration for bid E is an Edward
2826 for the surplus sale of evidence
seized firearms in department owned
firearms for the Cheyenne Police
Department. Uh five biders did respond
to this bid uh which I reviewed. Uh my
recommendation is to accept the highest
bid from ProForce Marketing Incorporated
out of Arizona. The total requested bid
award is $48,638.70
for the sale of 235 firearms. I stand
for any questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for the detective?
>> Mr. Chairman,
>> Councilman Renie,
>> this is kind of just tangential, but how
often do we have a sale like this?
>> Uh, Mr. Mr. Chairman, through you um
both with department firearms and then
the evidence seized firearms that we are
selling uh every every several years uh
depending on how old our firearms are
getting. Uh the department firearms we
have currently are pretty much brand
new. So we're selling a lot of our old
stock and that should refresh most of
that. And then as far as the evidence
seized firearms, there's a schedule of
how long we have to keep them uh in our
custody before we can dispose of them.
So, it's kind of random as to when we
accumulate so many and we lose space in
our evidence locker and then we are able
to sell them statutoily. So,
Council Wolf,
>> Mr. Chairman, thank you through you.
Thank you very much, sir. Um, are the
the purchasers, do they all have to be
licensed firearms uh purveyors? And
>> Mr. Chairman, through you uh ProForce,
so yes, they all have to have a federal
firearms license. uh Pro Force, we've
worked with them in the past. They are a
large company that provides uh they're
basically a law enforcement equipment
company. So, they buy a lot of these
firearms at a pretty good price and then
they can also supply us with other
stuff. So, so they are a fedally
firearms licensed company and and we
have worked with them in the past.
>> Great. Thank you. Thank you, sir. Thank
you.
>> Okay. Thank you, detective. We'll go to
public comment in the room. Any public
comment in the room?
Public comment online.
Any public comment online? Okay. Back to
the committee. What's your pleasure?
>> Mr. Chairman, uh, I move to accept the
bid from ProForce Marketing, Inc. in an
amount of $48,638.70.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
second by Councilman Moody. Any further
discussion?
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. sharing through you.
And just for the public to know, just
know that when they say evidences, it's
not we don't have a red flag law here in
Wyoming, say like in California, New
Jersey. So you probably seen it on the
news where like the Los Angeles Police
Department, New York, it's not that at
all. Okay? These are ones that were
commissioned in a crime. They have to be
seized. That's all 50 states. So just to
clarify that, just remember, we do not
have that. So, it's none of that going
on or people that use them in
self-defense, they do get them back.
That's Wyoming law. Thank you.
>> Thank you for that clarification,
Councilman. All in favor signify by
saying I.
And that that vote is unanimous to the
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to accept the bid. Next
item
>> number 27J. Consideration to purchase
between the city of Cheyenne and
complete ice arena services for the
purchase of a used Olympia Millennium
Esteel Ice Reservicer for the Ice and
Event Center.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair, Jason Sanchez, Community
Wreck and Events. Before you and for
your consideration is for us to purchase
a used ice groomer for the ice and event
center. We generally purchase uh new
equipment, but this unit was used by an
NHL team that the unit has been properly
maintained and has a lot of upgrades.
It's been reviewed by uh Brian Bell and
our staff. U this unit again is 10 years
old, but the cost is $128,000.
Uh for comparison, a new unit would run
$242,790,
and it will be replacing a 30-year-old
unit that we currently utilize. Um, I
will stand by for questions,
>> comments or questions for the committee
for the director. Councilman ready.
>> Does it have NHL logos on it?
>> Mr. Chair, you know it does not.
>> Thank you.
>> Right.
We should get some.
All right. Any public comment in the
room? Public comment in the room. Any
public comment online?
Public comment online.
Now back to the committee. What's your
pleasure?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve the
bid in the amount not to or the contract
in the amount not to exceed $128,400.
>> Second. It's been moved by Councilman
Rainey, second by Councilman Wolf.
All those in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> That vote is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to approve. Next item
>> number 27 K. Consideration to purchase
between the city of Cheyenne and Sans
Sarah for camera hardware and software
for the Cheyenne Transit Program transit
vehicles.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon chair and committee
members. I'm TJ Bartlebort, purchasing
manager. The Cheyenne Transit Program is
requesting approval to purchase camera
hardware, software, and a 36-month
software licensing licensing agreement
from Samsara. This purchase will equip
the Cheyenne Transit Program's entire
fleet of 20 public transit buses and
vans with with an integrated camera
system. The hardwell will remain an
asset of the city and will be
transferred to replacement vehicles as
the fleet is up as the fleet is updated
in future years. The camera data is
securely stored in Samsara's cloud
servers. This is a sole source purchase.
Therefore, competitive bids were not
solicited. Uh the system will provide
driver-f facing cameras to monitor
safety events and support driver
coaching and training when incidents
occur. Integration with the existing
onboard camera systems and GPS and
engine diagnostics to provide fleet
maintenance with real-time vehicle
location and operational data. Staff
recommends approval of the consideration
to purchase between the city and
Sanssara in the amount of $133,44.72.
Happy to answer any questions you have.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for staff?
>> Have two questions.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Thanks, Mr. Turn. Uh, thank you, sir.
Again, if you can't answer it, I
understand. But, um, I was looking this
on the page. It said camera connectors,
cables to pull third party camera feeds.
What does that mean?
>> Chair through you to Councilman Moody.
So the the existing fleet of buses that
we have do have surveillance cameras in
them already on kind of a standalone
hard drive basis. So I think that those
cables would be used to connect the
Samsara cloud connected software to the
existing hardware that's already on the
buses in addition to the new cameras
that would be installed. That hope that
answers your question.
>> Okay. Follow M. Councilman Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, sir. Appreciate that.
Um, how secure is this uh iCloud?
>> Chair through you to Councilman Moody.
Uh, Samar is a pretty nationally
recognized fleet camera operations
company. I'm pretty sure that they're I
would assume I don't know for certain,
but I think that they have pretty
high-tech encryption on all of their
software and their their data storage.
They're a pretty large company, so I
would assume pretty secure.
>> Yeah. Councilman Rainey, did you have a
question?
Okay, we'll go to public comment in the
room. Any public comment in the room?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
online.
Any public comment online?
Okay, see none. Come back to the
committee. What's your pleasure,
Mr. Chairman? Uh, I move to approve in
an amount not to exceed $133,44.72.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Wolf. Second by
Councilman Renie. Any further comments
or discussions? Councilman Moody.
>> Uh, thank Mr. Chairman through you. I'm
going to vote against this in committee
today because I do have some other
questions that are lingering in my mind
about this because I know we've been
looking a lot with the cameras and all
that. Again,
if there's others that can come to our
city council meeting the following
Monday to answer those questions and
that way there can be more public
engagement, that'd be great. Thank you.
>> Council Wolf, do you have any comments?
>> Oh, I'm sorry.
>> All in favor signify by saying I.
Opposed?
The recommendation of the finance
committee at the next meeting of the
governing body will be to approve with
Councilman Moody voting no. Next item
>> number 27 L consideration of RFP number
6-26 for a contract between the city of
Cheyenne and FCI con constructors of
Wyoming for the construction manager at
risk services for Cheyenne municipal
building renovation and potential city
building
city council building and second floor
municipal court renovation
>> staff report.
>> Adele Bartell, public works staff
engineer.
Um, for a total of $30,000, FCI will
provide CM services for the municipal
complex renovation project and with them
they will bring their expertise
um to allow cost savings for the project
with accurate cost estimating and their
knowledge of the market. um time savings
with their um knowledge of material lead
times and schedule development and their
ability for early procurement of
materials and they will bring expertise
to improve constructibility. I'll take
any questions you have.
>> Council Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Chairman 3. Uh thank
you, ma'am. So, I realize this is with
the sixth penny. What if that six penny
fails? What happens with this contract?
>> Oh,
uh, chairman threw you to Councilman
Moody. So, just to confirm that the
contract that before you is today,
that's before you today is just for
preconstruction services. That's why
it's capped at $30,000. We do have the
funding listed between general fund and
the six penny uh special purpose option
tax for the municipal building. So the
city council building and the municipal
court would be paid from general fund
and then municipal building from the
spot tax. So that's just for
pre-construction services. At the time
that uh FCI prepares their guaranteed
maximum price, that contract for
construction services would come before
the governing body again for final
consideration and that will more closely
align with uh passage of or
understanding of how that vote uh came
out through the ballot. So, director
Neanchek is here as well. She might
elaborate on that some more. director
>> Vicky Neichek public works just our
direction at this point is to continue
uh that direction really was given
through the citizens to design um at the
$2.5 million that they awarded us to
design. That's where the money's coming
from and we will complete that design.
>> Any further comments or questions? Let's
see our city treasurer wants to
>> deputy city treasurer. I just wanted to
let you know there's about $900,000 left
in that ballot
>> 2021.
>> Yep.
>> Thank you.
Any further questions from the
committee?
>> Um Mr. Chairman,
>> thank you through you. Um Adele, maybe
just for the benefit of the public who's
not familiar with this the whole notion
of uh uh contractor at risk um
management, how how does this play in on
the overall approach, which I fully
support what you're doing and and moving
forward with this and also because we
had the funding already. Um but if you
could just explain that a little bit and
and then what happens when we actually
go to um construction uh and
construction documents.
>> Uh Mr. Chair through you. So the CM um
is basically the um contractors acting
as another designer, another um
consultant uh to help our architects
with the um project and to make sure
that our design is
um as best as it can be because we only
get one shot to do do it right. Um and
as far as when it goes to the actual
construction, um it will make the
process so much faster.
Um like I said, they can expedite
the timeline with uh early procurement
of materials. They can even start site
developments sooner. Um,
and
they would most likely be the the um
contractors working on the whole
project. So, they they will have all of
the information as soon as it needs to
be built.
>> Any other questions for staff?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room.
Mr. White through you, Mr. Chairman.
Michael White. I I want to thank Vicki
for clarifying the process for the
30,000, but uh I still have a problem
with this because the borders haven't
approved this. Number one. Number two,
um I have great respect for FCI, but
number the question a few questions I
have. um when FCI was uh awarded this uh
consideration,
how did the city go about choosing them?
I realized there were two other
contractors. Number two,
when
I look at construction managers, fine,
but where I look at the expertise
and the risk to the public and the risk
to the people that vote, that's with the
architects and the engineers. That's
what they get paid for.
But the other questions I have is that
they've been given this today. if they
do get it. I still feel that this
premature, but thanks for Vicki saying
that we did vote on that.
But the other question I would have is
that when this is all said and done and
the bids and the contracts do come out
with the plans,
do any other contractors, wherever
they're from, do they have the issue of
the ability to actually bid on the
project? Thank you.
You want to take that one TJ
>> chair? Uh through you to Mr. White's
comments. I'll speak primarily on the
selection process and then we do have
Ross from FCI here with us. I might
invite right Ross to come up and give us
a little bit of background on how the
subcontractors get hired for the actual
construction of the project. So this was
uh uh advertised as a request for
proposal. So we evaluate evaluate it in
in accordance with our normal processes.
We have a a scorecard matrix of scoring
criteria for uh qualifications,
timeline, expertise. Uh and then we also
rate their fee schedules. The
construction manager at risk is very
different than a design bid builds kind
of contract and that uh the design's not
done yet. So that's why we're here just
talking pre-construction services. But
they provide us what their markup is on
materials and what their they tell us
what their profit fee will be and that's
how we generate what the guaranteed
maximum price is. But uh FCI was the
number one ranked firm as a result of
the technical scoring of their proposal
and then a subsequent interview process
with all three firms and they were
ranked as the number one company. So
that's why we're here recommending them
for award.
>> Mr. Ross,
>> Mr. Chairman, Councilman, uh my name is
Ross Show. I am the senior project
manager with FCI Constructors. I'm
actually also listed on this project. Um
to answer the question that Mr. White
had, um it's kind of a two-step process
here. First step is as the design team
is going through the process of
developing drawings
um the $30,000 that has been awarded to
FC or hopefully will be awarded to FCI
constructors that pays for us to put
estimates to those current design
drawings. So as the as the process of
drawings go through, we are also
providing estimates based upon those
drawings to make sure that we are in the
ballpark of where we expect the budget
needs to be at in order for it to to
actually start construction after the
one penny sales tax passes. Now, um, as
far as the bidding process,
actually, let me let's back up just a
little bit on key or during the design
phase and also during the, um, practice
of of putting together budgets,
estimates for those design drawings. Not
only does FCI constructors look at
those, but we also reach out to um, key
subcontractors, mainly mechanical and
electrical. um if there's any special
parts and pieces of the project, we
reach out to those subcontractors.
Normally, we reach out to local
subcontractors, be it MSI,
um Climate Control, Advanced Sheet
Metals, um again, the ones that we have
all seen forever um and ask those
companies to also take a look at the
drawings. And we usually get different
um percentages of drawings during the
phases. You know, 30% 50% um 75% CD or
not, excuse me, DD drawings. We have
those subs, those different subs look at
it during the different phases. So,
we're not just going to one sub um and
asking him and going over and over. We
want everyone to have a fair market and
a fair chance to look at it.
Once the drawings reach CDs,
construction design or construction
development drawings, um the state of
Wyoming has some pretty good um
guidelines that the bidding process that
we are required to meet goes through. So
yes, every single subcontractor,
local or even out of state, has an
opportunity to bid the dr to bid the
documents and we still also apply the 5%
preference um for for local
subcontractors.
Council Wolf. Uh, Mr. Chairman, thank
you very much through you. Um, thank
you, sir, for coming. Um, SEI has um and
I I know this from my prior life. Um,
long history of constructing really
significant buildings within this state.
I know you've constructed schools uh
constructed buildings on the university
campus um and um and and from from my
observation I think getting you involved
in the project now just adds a whole
layer of additional expertise from uh
very very experienced contractors who um
who actually are in the marketplace
every day trying to figure out uh what
kinds of project what kind of uh
components to to build and and how to
estimate their costs. So, um I think
this is a terrific idea and I appreciate
you coming and and uh speaking with us.
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, through you. Uh thank
you. Yes. I mean uh
we we have been here FCI Constructors
has been here since around 2005. I've
been here since 2006. I've raised my
family here. Um my wife has has worked
here. I have worked here. We've never
left here.
>> Councilman Rainey.
>> Yep. Mr. Chairman, I think my question
may be more directed towards staff, but
um kind of as a follow-up to Mr. White's
question. I had had assumed also that
the architectural firm that was doing
the design will be providing us cost
estimates. So then does FCI review those
and
is there discussion if they don't match
up or they don't think they're
consistent? I mean can someone tell me
how that works?
>> Mr. Chairman through you. Um yes, I do
believe that plan one um who is the
architectural firm that has been hired
um they have been providing you um cost
estimates based upon the drawings that
they currently have um which right now
if again TJ please correct me if I'm
wrong here um the drawings that I have
seen um are pretty detailed through the
um city municipal building um that's
where I'm guessing that you have seen
those cost estimates um is on those
drawings but where it comes to the
senior center remodel and also the
second floor um
second floor courthouse uh remodel or
tenant finish. Um I have not seen um
drawings, you know, complete drawings or
even close to complete drawings on
those. That is where um we'll probably
start taking over on some of those cost
estimates. But to answer your question
also as plan one does go through and
provide their cost estimates again this
is one of the benefits of a CR process
where we're all sitting on the same type
side of the table um so there are no
secrets um because ultimately it is the
city of Cheyenne's money and we all take
that very very seriously and so when we
look at our estimate um and we're
looking at plan ones we're all looking
at it together and we're trying to
figure out you know what what is the
best for the project. Hopefully that
answers your question.
>> It does. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Any further comments or questions from
the committee or the representative from
FCI?
None. Any further public comment?
Any public comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
Any public comment online? You seeing
none, we'll come back to the committee.
What's your pleasure?
Mr. Chairman, I move to approve an
amount not to exceed $30,000
three $30,000 for pre-construction
services.
>> Been moved by Councilman Wolf, second by
Councilman Rainy. Any further
discussion.
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> Any opposed?
>> No.
The recommendation of the finance
committee at the next meeting of the
governing body will be to approve with
Councilman Moody voting no. Seeing that
there are no more further items front of
the finance committee on this agenda, we
are adjourned.